Finding Aid for George Romney Papers 1920s-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Governor's Papers
  - Governor's Office
    - Staff Files
      - Legal Department (Robert Danhof) 1963-1968
        - Civil Disorders 1964-1968
          - General 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 319)
          - Baraga County Flood 1968 (Box 319)
          - Benton Harbor
            - 1966 (Box 319)
            - 1968 (Box 319)
          - Big Rapids area tornado 1968 (Box 319)
          - Detroit Riot 1967
            - General (Box 319)
            - Chronology of Events (Box 319)
            - Emergency Procedures and Executive Orders (Box 319)
            - Evidence File (Box 319)
            - Federal Troops, Request for (Box 319)
            - Legislator Letters Requesting Federal Assistance (Box 319)
            - President's Proclamation and Executive order (Box 319)
            - Staff Assignments (Box 319)
            - State Police Reports (Box 319)
            - Vance (Cyrus) Report on Riot (Box 319)
          - Flint (Box 319)
          - Grand Rapids
            - 1967 (Box 319)
            - 1968 (Box 319)
          - Guard Call-up 1968 (Box 319)
          - Hazel Park Race Track Closing (Box 319)
          - Hillsdale (Essex Wire Corporation) 1964 (Box 319)
          - Kent County tornado 1967 (Box 319)
          - MacClellan Committee (testimony before) (Box 319)
          - Macomb County (Box 319)
          - National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders (Box 319)
          - Oakland County, 2 folders (Box 319)
          - Saginaw (Box 319)
          - Wayne County, 2 folders (Box 319)
        - Civil Rights (statement from Michigan State Advisory Committee to the U.S. Civil Rights Commission and the Michigan Civil Rights Commission) 1968 (Box 315)
        - Civil Rights Commission 1963 (Box 315)
        - Clinton County Prosecutor (Box 315)
        - Cohan, Leon (deputy attorney general) 1966-1968 (Box 315)
        - Commerce, Department of 1966-1968 (Box 315)
        - Committee of 100 1966 (Box 315)
        - Corporations and Securities Commission 1963-1965 (Box 315)
        - Corrections, Department of, memoranda 1963-1968, 2 folders (Box 315)
        - Council of State Governments (Box 315)
        - County Home Rule reports 1964 (Box 315)
        - Court administrator 1968 (Box 315)
        - Court clinic 1963-1964 (Box 315)
        - Court Reorganization, Joint Committee on 1963-1968 (Box 315)
        - Court Reorganization (lower court) 1967-1968 (Box 316)
        - Crime 1968 (Box 316)
        - Crime Commission reports 1967-1968 (Box 316)
        - Crime Commission correspondence and memoranda 1967-1968 (Box 316)
        - Crime statistics 1967 (Box 316)
        - Crippled Children Commission 1962-1963 (Box 316)
        - Crippled Children Commission (director) 1963 (Box 316)
        - Departmental Communications 1967-1968 (Box 316)
        - Derengoski, Robert 1967-1968 (Box 316)
        - Detroit Police Dispute Panel 1968 (Box 316)
        - Detroit Riot 1967-1968 [see box 319] (Box 316)
        - DeVries (Walt) memo 1967 (Box 316)
        - Dow Chemical (Box 316)
        - Economic Expansion, Michigan Department of 1963 (Box 316)
        - Election Law Task Force 1965 (Box 316)
        - Election Law questions 1967-1968 (Box 316)
        - Election night 1966 (Box 316)
        - Election (special election) 1968 (Box 316)
        - Electoral College
          - 1964 (Box 316)
          - 1968 (Box 316)
        - Extradition
          - Hunt, Ernestine 1967 (Box 316)
          - Law, Donald 1968 (Box 316)
          - McDonald, Willie 1967 (Box 316)
        - Fairwood Medical Center Investigation 1966 (Box 316)
        - Federal Fair Labor Standards Act case 1967 (Box 316)
        - Flood damage, Warren and Madison Heights 1967 (Box 316)
        - Folmar, Bishop C.H. 1968 (Box 316)
        - Grand Jury investigation of Highway Department 1967 (Box 317)
        - Great Lakes River Basin Commission 1965-1966 (Box 317)
        - Griffin, Robert P. 1966 (Box 317)
        - Grodman, Irving 1965-1967 (Box 317)
        - Gubernatorial Succession 1964 (Box 317)
        - Hare, James M. 1966 (Box 317)
        - Higher Education Facilities Commission/Higher Education Assistance Authority merger 1967 (Box 317)
        - Highway Department 1967 (Box 317)
        - Hospitals, see Labor Mediation (Box 317)
        - Human Resources Council 1966 (Box 317)
        - I-696 location problem 1966 (Box 317)
        - Insurance Department 1963-1968 (Box 317)
        - Insurance (Unsatisfied Judgment Fund) 1965 (Box 317)
        - Intergovernmental Cooperation, Michigan Commission on 1967-1968 (Box 317)
        - Internal Revenue (agreement with Michigan) 1964 (Box 317)
        - Interstate Cooperative Commission 1965 (Box 317)
        - Jackson Prison (memo) 1967 (Box 317)
        - Jackson Prison Arsenal Explosion 1967 (Box 317)
        - Judicial Review 1963-1966 (Box 317)
        - Judicial Selection Committee 1963-1964 (Box 317)
        - Kellogg Company dispute with Elevator Board 1968 (Box 317)
        - Kuhn, Richard (complaints) 1966-1967 (Box 317)
        - Labor, Department of (Box 317)
        - Labor mediation/strikes
          - Detroit newspaper strike 1967-1968 (Box 317)
          - Flint city strike 1968 (Box 317)
          - Ford Motor 1966 (Box 317)
          - General 1966-1968 (Box 317)
          - Hospitals
            - Burgess Hospital, Kalamazoo 1968 (Box 317)
            - Boulevard General, Detroit 1968 (Box 317)
            - Lakeview Hospital, Battle Creek 1968 (Box 317)
            - St. Joseph Hospital, Hancock 1968 (Box 317)
            - Sparrow Hospital, Lansing 1965 (Box 317)
          - Hutchinson Act 1966 (Box 317)
          - Lansing City strike 1966 (Box 317)
          - Lansing Firemen strike 1968 (Box 317)
          - Schools
            - Cherry Hill Schools 1967 (Box 317)
            - Detroit, 1967 (Box 317)
            - Education meeting 1967 (Box 317)
            - Ferris Institute 1967 (Box 317)
            - General 1966-1967 (Box 317)
            - Gibraltar 1967 (Box 317)
            - Holland 1967 (Box 317)
            - Inkster 1968 (Box 317)
            - Van Buren School District 1966 (Box 317)
          - South Haven rubber strike 1968 (Box 317)
          - Steel hauling dispute 1967 (Box 317)
          - Teamsters strike 1967-1968 (Box 317)
        - Labor: Michigan State Employees Union 1966 (Box 317)
        - Labor: Minimum Wage 1962 (Box 317)
        - Labor Reorganization 1963 (Box 317)
        - Lake County 1964 (Box 317)
        - Landrum-Griffin Act 1966 (Box 317)
        - Legislation (arranged by topic)
          - Budget, Joint Committee on 1967 (Box 318)
          - Chiropractic Regulations (H.B. 3381), 1966 (Box 318)
          - Condemnation Statutes Revision 1965 (Box 318)
          - Conflict of Interest (H.B. 3512; 3513) 1968 (Box 318)
          - Consumer Installment Loan Act (S.B. 608) 1968 (Box 318)
          - Council of State Government (H.B. 2830) 1968 (Box 318)
          - Crime legislation (miscellaneous) 1967-1968 (Box 318)
          - Dram Shop (H.B. 62) 1964 (Box 318)
          - Federal Standards Bill 1965 (Box 318)
          - General 1964-1968 (Box 318)
          - Interstate Taxation (HR 16491) 1966-1967 (Box 318)
          - Michigan Administrative Procedure Act 1967 (Box 318)
          - Mineral Rights (S.B. 952) 1966 (Box 318)
          - Occupational Health and Safety Act (see box 339) (Box 318)
          - Open Occupancy Bill (see box 339) (Box 318)
          - Plat Act 1967 (Box 318)
          - Pollution Control Bonds 1968 (Box 318)
          - Safe Streets Legislation 1968 (Box 318)
          - Silicosis Bill 1967 (Box 318)
          - State Housing Authority 1966 (Box 318)
          - Tax Court (H.B. 3853) 1966 (Box 318)
          - Tax Legislation (see box 324) (Box 318)
          - Uniform Apportionment for Income Tax Purposes 1965 (Box 318)
          - Uniform Food Law 1966 (Box 318)
          - Veterans Homestead Tax Relief 1966-1967 (Box 318)
          - Workmen's Compensation 1965-1966 (Box 318)
          - Youthful Offender Act (Box 318)
        - Legislative Recount 1966 (Box 320)
        - Legislator memoranda 1967 (Box 320)
        - Liberato, Ralph 1967 (Box 320)
        - Lieutenant Governor, powers of 1965 (Box 320)
        - Liquor Control Commission 1965-1968 (Box 320)
        - Licensing and Regulation, Department of 1967-1968 (Box 320)
        - Livingston County Investigation 1968 (Box 320)
        - Mackinac Island (governor's residence) 1966 (Box 320)
        - Mackinac Island legislative meeting 1966 (Box 320)
        - Mackinac Island State Park Commission 1964-1965 (Box 320)
        - Macomb County tornado 1964 (Box 320)
        - Medicaid 1967 (Box 320)
        - Medicare report 1965 (Box 320)
        - Meeting of department heads 1967 (Box 320)
        - Memoranda (governor)
          - 1963-1964 (Box 320)
          - 1965-1966 (Box 320)
          - 1967 (Box 320)
          - 1968 (Box 320)
        - Memoranda (staff)
          - 1963-1964 (Box 320)
          - 1965-1966 (Box 320)
          - 1967 (Box 320)
          - 1968 (Box 320)
        - Mental Health, Department of 1966-1967 (Box 321)
        - Michigan Economic Opportunity Office 1964-1965 (Box 321)
        - Military Affairs 1965-1966 (Box 321)
        - Military Affairs (Rental of Armory) 1966 (Box 321)
        - Military Establishment reorganization 1965-1966 (Box 321)
        - Miscellaneous 1963-1968 (Box 321)
        - Multistate Tax Commission 1965-1968 (Box 321)
        - National Guard
          - General 1967-1968 (Box 321)
          - Ronald McDonald case
            - 1963-1964 (Box 321)
            - 1965 (Box 321)
            - 1966-1968 (Box 321)
            - Court of Appeals decision (Box 321)
        - National Tax Association
          - 1963 (Box 321)
          - 1964 (Box 321)
          - 1965 (Box 321)
          - 1966 (Box 321)
          - 1967 (Box 321)
        - Notary Public Programs 1965-1966 (Box 321)
        - Northern Michigan University demonstration 1967 (Box 321)
        - Nursing, Board of 1962-1963 (Box 321)
        - Nursing Homes 1963 (Box 321)
        - Oakland County Grand Jury 1966 (Box 322)
        - Office Management meetings 1965 (Box 322)
        - Oil and Gas rules 1963 (Box 322)
        - Outdoor Advertising 1967 (Box 322)
        - Parks and Recreation Committee 1963 (Box 322)
        - Peoples Community Hospital Authority 1965-1966 (Box 322)
        - Pharmacy, Board of
          - David Moss case 1963-1964 (Box 322)
          - SuperX Drug Corp. case 1965-1966 (Box 322)
          - General 1965-1966 (Box 322)
        - Pittenger, Phil 1966 (Box 322)
        - Police
          - Legal Advisor Program 1967 (Box 322)
        - Poverty Program 1965-1968 (Box 322)
        - Probate Judges Salary 1967 (Box 322)
        - Property Tax Exemptions, Governor's Committee on 1964-1966 (Box 322)
        - Prosecuting Attorneys Association 1967 (Box 322)
        - Prosecuting attorney's recommendations 1966-1967 (Box 322)
        - Prosecutors' meeting
          - 1963 (Box 322)
          - 1966 (Box 322)
        - Public Employees' Study Group 1966-1968 (Box 322)
        - Public Health, Department of 1965-1968 (Box 322)
        - Public Safety Committee 1966-1967 (Box 322)
        - Public Service Commission 1965 (Box 322)
        - Racing Commissioner 1967-1968 (Box 322)
        - Removal
          - Buback, Peter (Wayne Co. sheriff) 1966-1968 (Box 322)
          - Hamtramck officials 1963-1964 (Box 322)
          - Maras, Rudolph H. 1967 (Box 322)
          - Memorandum re: removal for cause 1963 (Box 322)
        - Reorganization (second phase) 1967 (Box 323)
        - Republican Lawyers Advisory Council 1965 (Box 323)
        - Republican State Central Committee 1963-1966 (Box 323)
        - Resolutions 1964 (Box 323)
        - Right of Wayne (Boyne Mountain) 1966 (Box 323)
        - Riot control and protection of firemen from sniping 1967 (Box 323)
        - Riot Protection Plan 1968 (Box 323)
        - Robos 1968, re: various topics (Box 323)
        - St. Clair Islands 1963 (Box 323)
        - Sanilac State Park 1963 (Box 323)
        - Small loans 1962-1963 (Box 323)
        - Souris, Theodore (resignation) 1968 (Box 323)
        - Special messages
          - Courts of limited jurisdiction 1967 (Box 323)
          - Local and urban affairs 1967 (Box 323)
          - Traffic safety 1967 (Box 323)
        - Special session of legislature 1967 (Box 323)
        - Speeches of GR
          - General 1963-1965 (Box 323)
          - State of State 1967 (Box 323)
          - State of State 1968 (Box 323)
        - State Bar Association: relations with the press May 1967 (Box 323)
        - State, Department of 1965-1967 (Box 323)
        - State Fair Stadium: Revisionary Rights 1965 (Box 323)
        - State Manpower Development Commission 1966 (Box 323)
        - State Military Board 1967-1968 (Box 323)
        - State Police
          - Miscellaneous 1965-1968 (Box 323)
          - Guidelines 1966-1967 (Box 323)
        - State Safety Commission 1967 (Box 323)
        - State Tax Commission (Appeals) 1966 (Box 323)
        - Supreme Court Recommendations for additional Judges 1967 (Box 323)
        - Taxes and Tax
          - Legislation 1965-1967, 2 portfolios (Box 324)
        - Tax Referendum 1967 (Box 324)
        - Tourist Program 1964 (Box 324)
        - Treasury Department 1964-1966 (Box 324)
        - Urban Problems, Special Commission on 1965-1966 (Box 324)
        - Waiting Week (unemployment) 1967 (Box 324)
        - Washtenaw County Jail Problem 1968 (Box 324)
        - Water Management and Planning 1967 (Box 324)
        - Water Resources 1966 (Box 324)
        - Wayne County Grand Jury 1965-1966 (Box 324)
        - Wayne County Special Elections 1965 (Box 324)
        - Welch, Thomas 1966 (Box 324)
        - West Central Organization 1965-1966 (Box 324)
        - Wisconsin-Michigan Boundary Commission 1966-1967 (Box 324)
        - Workmen's Compensation 1962-1963 (Box 324)
        - Ypsilanti Township Parks Commission 1964-1965 (Box 324)
      - Theodore Blizzard
        - Agriculture
          - Administrative (Box 325)
          - Budget (Box 325)
          - Commission on Agriculture (Box 325)
          - Dairy Imports (Box 325)
          - Farm Bureau (Box 325)
          - Meat Inspection (Box 325)
          - National Farm Organization holding order for milk (Box 325)
          - Potato Industry (Box 325)
          - Rural Development Pilot Project (Box 325)
          - State Fair (Box 325)
        - Mental Health
          - Audits (Box 325)
          - Austerity Budget (Box 325)
          - Budget (Box 325)
          - Director Appointment
            - General (Box 325)
            - Anderson, William (Box 325)
            - Glass, Albert (Box 325)
            - Lowry, James V. (Box 325)
          - Forensic Psychiatry (Box 325)
          - Inter-Agency Committee on Retardation (Box 325)
          - Ionia State Hospital (Box 325)
          - Legislation 1968 (Box 325)
          - Public Act 54 (Box 325)
          - Recovery, Inc. (Box 325)
        - Migrants
          - Alfaro, Ruben (Box 325)
          - Chavez, Tomas (Box 325)
          - Civil Rights Commission (Box 325)
          - Correspondence (Box 325)
          - Governor's Commission on Migrant Labor (Box 325)
          - Health Programs (Public Health Department) (Box 325)
          - Health Programs (Tri-County Report) (Box 325)
          - Housing Legislation (Box 326)
          - Labor Department Programs (Box 326)
          - Legislation 1965, 1967, 2 folders (Box 326)
          - Migrant March March 1967 (Box 326)
        - Program Information
          - Community Schools (Box 326)
          - Mind Inc. (Box 326)
          - Talking Typewriter (Box 326)
        - Public Health
          - Abortion and Sterilization (Box 326)
          - Advisory Council (Box 326)
          - Air Pollution Control Commission (Box 326)
          - Air Quality Act of 1967 (Box 326)
          - Alcoholism (Box 326)
          - Ambulance Service (Box 326)
          - Comprehensive Health Planning, Advisory Council (Box 326)
          - Computer Utilization (Box 326)
          - Crippled Children's Program (Box 326)
          - Dental Survey (Box 326)
          - Director Recruitment (Box 326)
          - Fluoridation (Box 326)
          - Forty, Committee of (Box 326)
          - Grand View Hospital (Box 326)
          - Health Statistics Center (Box 326)
          - Highway Safety and Medical Problems (Box 326)
          - Hospital Disaster Plan (Box 326)
          - Hospital Privileges (Box 326)
          - Iron County Hospitals, 2 folders (Box 326)
          - Legislative Programs (Box 326)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 326)
          - New Programs (Box 326)
          - Reorganization (Box 326)
          - Restaurant Inspection (Box 326)
          - Solid Waste Disposal (Box 327)
          - Solid Waste Act of 1965 (Box 327)
          - State Planning Project (Box 327)
          - Veterans' Facility (Box 327)
        - State Programming, Institute on (Box 327)
        - University of Management Technology 1967 (Box 327)
        - Urban Problems, Special Commission on (Box 327)
        - Vocational Rehabilitation (Box 327)
      - Charles Orlebeke
        - Agriculture, Department of 1966-1968 (Box 327)
        - Arts, Michigan Council for the (Box 327)
        - Budget and Fiscal Reform Message (Box 327)
        - Camp Highfields 1966 (Box 327)
        - Civil Rights
          - General (Box 327)
          - Blue Cross-Blue Shield controversy 1966 (Box 327)
          - National Guard directives, etc. 1964-1965 (Box 327)
        - Civil Rights Commission 1963-1965 (Box 327)
        - Civil Rights Conference (College Republicans), February 5-6, 1966 (Box 327)
        - Civil Rights Conference, April 26-27, 1966, 2 folders (Box 327)
        - Crime, Delinquency and Criminal Administration, Commission on (Box 327)
        - Education
          - Budget 1968 (Box 327)
          - Central Michigan University 1966-1968 (Box 327)
          - Community Colleges (Box 327)
          - Correspondence (miscellaneous) (Box 327)
          - Council of College Presidents 1963-1965 (Box 327)
          - Detroit Schools 1967-1968 (Box 327)
          - Eastern Michigan University 1967 (Box 327)
          - Ferris State College 1966-1968 (Box 327)
          - Finance/Fiscal Reform (Box 327)
          - Higher Education
            - Citizens Committee on Higher Education (Box 328)
            - Federal Aid to (Box 328)
            - Private Colleges, Financial Assistance to (Box 328)
            - Space Utilization Study (Box 328)
            - State Master Plan (Box 328)
            - Statistics (Box 328)
          - Inkster Schools 1968 (Box 328)
          - Michigan Education Association (Box 328)
          - Private Education (Box 328)
          - School Aid (Box 328)
          - Speeches (Box 328)
          - State Scholarship Plan (Box 328)
          - Sumpter School (Box 328)
          - Superintendent Recruitment (Box 328)
        - Employment of the Handicapped, Governor's Commission on 1963-1967 (Box 328)
        - Fair Employment Practices Commission 1962-1963 (Box 328)
        - Human Resource Council, 2 folders (Box 329)
        - Indian Affairs Commission 1964-1968 (Box 329)
        - Interstate Cooperation, Governor's Committee on (Box 329)
        - Medicaid (Box 329)
        - Medicare (Box 329)
        - Mental Health Advisory Council (Box 329)
        - Mental Health (Budget) (Box 329)
        - Mental Health Council of Private Organizations (Box 329)
        - Mental Health Department Organization (Box 329)
        - Mental Health (Federal Program) (Box 329)
        - Mental Health (General) (Box 329)
        - Mental Health (Jackson Prison clinic) (Box 329)
        - Mental Health (Legal) (Box 329)
        - Migrant Labor Families 1967 (Box 329)
        - Narcotics/Narcotics Addiction, 2 folders (Box 329)
        - Neighborhood Services Program (Box 330)
        - Northwood Institute (Box 330)
        - Parochiaid (Box 330)
        - Position statements on various issues (Box 330)
        - Race Cranks (Box 330)
        - Reapportionment (Box 330)
        - Republican Party (Box 330)
        - State Police (Civil Defense) (Box 330)
        - Time (Daylight Savings) (Box 330)
        - Urban Problems, Special Commission on (Box 330)
        - Water Resources Research (Box 330)
        - West Central Organization (Box 330)
        - Youth Commission 1966-1967 (Box 330)
      - Charles Harmon
        - Papers re: GR's tax message 1967 (Box 331)
        - Constituent mail received, January 1969, re: GR's speech on parochiaid (Box 331)
      - Walt DeVries
        - Budgetary Materials, 1964/65, 2 folders (Box 331)
        - Health Care (material received from Arthur Whittaker) 1962-1963
          - Notebook 1962-1963 (Box 331)
          - Commissions and agencies (Box 331)
          - Prepayment Voluntary Health Insurance (Box 331)
          - Non-governmental Agencies (Box 331)
          - Health in Industry (Box 331)
          - Medical Education in Michigan (Box 331)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 331)
      - William Whitbeck
        - Agriculture Commission (Box 332)
        - Alewife Pollution 1967-1968 (Box 332)
        - Civil Rights Commission 1968 (Box 332)
        - Fair Housing 1967-1968 (Box 332)
        - National Guard 1967-1968 (Box 332)
        - Recreation/Conservation 1964-1967 (Box 332)
        - Riots 1968 (Box 332)
        - Transportation 1965-1967 (Box 332)
      - Herbert DeJong
        - Agriculture
          - New Programs for 1967-1968 1966 (Box 332)
          - Reorganization 1965-1967 (Box 332)
        - Health
          - General 1965-1966 (Box 332)
          - Air Pollution (Box 332)
          - Health Department (data processing) (Box 332)
          - Heart Disease, Cancer and Stroke (Advisory Council) 1965 (Box 332)
          - Hill-Burton Grants to Peoples Community Hospital Authority 1965 (Box 332)
          - Local Health Department Committee (re: formula grants) 1964-1965 (Box 332)
          - Michigan Health Council 1964-1965 (Box 332)
          - Osteopathic College (Box 332)
          - Public Health Service Hospital 1965 (Box 332)
          - Rehabilitation Careers (Box 332)
          - Tuberculosis legislation 1966 (Box 332)
          - Tuberculosis Sanitorium, Copper Country 1965-1966 (Box 333)
        - Medicare
          - General 1965-1966, 3 folders (Box 333)
          - Cost 1966 (Box 333)
          - Crippled Children 1966 (Box 333)
          - Medical Management 1966 (Box 333)
        - Upper Great Lakes Regional Commission 1966 (Box 333)
        - Upper Peninsula Committee for Area Progress 1964-1966 (Box 333)
        - Urban Renewal (Box 333)
        - Veterans, Education of Children of 1966 (Box 333)
        - Youth Commission
          - Appointments 1963-1966 (Box 333)
          - Action Package 1964 (Box 333)
        - Youth Program 1964-1966 (Box 333)
      - Area Interests
        - Civil Defense
          - Joseph Child's file 1965 (Box 334)
          - Advisory Council Meeting 1965 (Box 334)
          - Emergency Planning 1964 (Box 334)
          - Emergency Planning 1965 (Box 334)
          - Emergency Resource Management Plan 1964 (Box 334)
          - Military Establishment (Box 334)
          - National Guard (Box 334)
        - Conservation/Recreation
          - Inter-agency Council for Recreation (Box 334)
          - Litter (Box 334)
          - Messages on 1966-1967 (Box 334)
          - Natural Beauty, Governor's Conference on, 1965, 4 folders (Box 334)
          - Porcupine Mountains 1965 (Box 334)
          - Recreation (General) 1965 (Box 334)